Guide to the HAWK Papers
University of Houston Libraries
HAWK Papers
1998-2006
06/2010-024
H.A.W.K. (Rapper)
0.25 linear feet
1 box; 1 oversized poster; 99 digital files (4.2 GB)
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
This collection includes materials pertaining to the life and rap career of John Edward Hawkins, or HAWK. Digital files comprise the bulk of the collection and mostly include digital photographs of HAWK and his associates at hip hop related events.
Biographical Information:
HAWK, also known as H.A.W.K. or Big Hawk, was born John Edward Hawkins in Houston on November 15, 1969. Both HAWK and his brother Patrick Lamark Hawkins, known as Fat Pat, became members of the Screwed Up Click, a group of Houston area rappers centered around the work of DJ Screw. HAWK often worked with DJ Screw to contribute raps to DJ Screw’s famous gray tapes, and he collaborated with Fat Pat, DJ Screw, and others to form the group Dead End Alliance (D.E.A) and Dead End Records.
HAWK released his first solo album, Under H.A.W.K.’s Wings, with Dead End Records in 2000. In 2002, he released his second album, HAWK.
On April 9, 2006, HAWK married his longtime girlfriend, Meshah Hawkins. Shortly thereafter, in May 2006, HAWK was shot and killed. His murder is unsolved.
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Genre/Form of Material:
Digital images; Notes; Personal papers
Topical Term:
Hip-hop -- Texas -- Houston; Hip-hop -- United States -- History; Rap (Music) -- Texas -- Houston; Rap musicians -- Texas -- Houston
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research
Acquisition Information
Information of acquisition method not available.
Related Materials:
DJ Screw Photographs and Memorabilia digital collection (http://digital.lib.uh.edu/collection/djscrew)
HAWK Photographs and Memorabilia digital collection (http://digital.lib.uh.edu/collection/hawk)
Scope and Contents
This collection includes materials pertaining to the life and rap career of John Edward Hawkins, or HAWK. Digital files comprise the bulk of the collection and mostly include digital photographs of HAWK and his associates at hip hop related events. The digital files also include personal family photographs of HAWK’s wedding and funeral, as well as scans of newspaper clippings pertaining to his death. All digital files were scanned from originals owned by HAWK’s family.
The collection also contains a smaller amount of physical material, including a notebook used by HAWK to record rap lyrics and his daily activities, promotional material, and the obituaries, or memorial service programs, for HAWK and his brother Fat Pat.
Detailed List of Contents
- Notebook
  Scope and Contents
  The notebook includes rap lyrics and information documenting HAWK’s daily life. The original item is fragile and use of the digital surrogate is preferred; please see http://digital.lib.uh.edu/collection/hawk/item/189
  - Notebook (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Promotional Materials
  - Street Wize Magazine Issue 8, with “Exclusive: HAWK’s Last Interview”, circa 2006 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 1)
  - Incredible HAWK photograph, undated (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 2)
- Personal Materials
  - Patrick Lamark Hawkins “Fat Pat” obituary (memorial service program), 1998 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 3)
  - John Edward Hawkins “HAWK” obituary (memorial service program), 2006 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 4)
  - Who Murdered Big HAWK poster, May 1, 2006 (Drawer F.3, Ovs folder 1)
- Digital Files
  The digital files can be accessed in the Special Collections Reading Room. Please note that the filename for each digital file is indicated in the inventory. A spreadsheet with original file name information is available by contacting the curator at jgrob@uh.edu.
  - Promotional and Event Photographs
    - Fat Pat, 2010-024_00001a.jpg–2010-024_00001b.jpg (Item 1)
    - Fat Pat “Ghetto Dreams” promotional photograph, 2010-024_00002.jpg (Item 2)
    - HAWK in Felony Flow shirt in front of backdrop, 2010-024_00003.jpg (Item 3)
    - HAWK in Original S.U.C. shirt in front of backdrop, 2010-024_00004.jpg–2010-024_00005.jpg (Item 4)
    - HAWK and Lil' O, 2010-024_00006.jpg (Item 5)
    - HAWK, Lil' Keke, and Big Pokey, 2010-024_00007.jpg (Item 6)
    - HAWK, “Ghetto Dreams” promotional photo, 2010-024_00008.jpg (Item 7)
    - HAWK on the mic, 2010-024_00009.jpg (Item 8)
    - HAWK in HAWK jacket, 2010-024_00010.jpg (Item 9)
    - HAWK and Trae in HAWK jacket in front of backdrop, 2010-024_00011.jpg (Item 10)
    - Meshah Hawkins and the Boudin Man in front of Screwed Up Click backdrop, 2010-024_00012.jpg (Item 11)
    - Big Moe, Priority Records promotional photo, 2010-024_00013.jpg (Item 12)
    - Screwed Up Click members, Back row: Ira, unknown, Big Pokey, Z-Ro, Trae, MJ; Middle row: Yungstar, Meshah Hawkins, Big Moe, Lil' Keke, Brandy, unknown; Front row: Chris Ward, Lil' O, Russell, Sam, Bird, 2010-024_00014.jpg (Item 13)
    - Screwed Up Click members at Screwed Up Records & Tapes, Back row: Mike D, HAWK, Big Pokey, Trae, Head, Mr. 3-2; Front row: Chris Ward, Lil' Keke, Big Moe, Lil’ O, Grace, 2010-024_00015.jpg (Item 14)
    - “The Fellas,” Standing: unknown, Russell, Stick 1; Sitting on car: unknown; Kneeling: T-Bone; Sitting on car: Kay-K, Black, unknown; Standing: Lil' Keke, 2010-024_00016.jpg (Item 15)
    - HAWK and friends, Standing: unknown, HAWK, Kay-K, T-Bone; Kneeling: unknown, Lil’ Black, 2010-024_00017.jpg (Item 16)
    - HAWK and the Grit Boys, Standing: Scooby, Niq, HAWK, unknown; Kneeling: Starchie Archie, Pat, 2010-024_00018.jpg (Item 17)
    - ESG Sipping Syrup, Peter Beste Photography, 2010-024_00019a.jpg–2010-024_00019b.jpg (Item 18)
    - HAWK in Felony Flow shirt, pointing, 2010-024_00020.jpg (Item 19)
    - HAWK on the mic, by Luxury Mindz Photography, 2010-024_00021.jpg (Item 20)
    - HAWK at Pen & Pixel shoot, 2010-024_00022.jpg–2010-024_00036.jpg (Item 21)
    - HAWK at Screwed Up Records & Tapes, 2010-024_00037.jpg (Item 22)
    - Lil' Keke at Screwed Up Records & Tapes, 2010-024_00038.jpg (Item 23)
    - Screwed Up Click members at Screwed Up Records & Tapes, Standing: Mike D, Lil’ 3rd, Chris Ward, Trae, Head, Grace, Big Pokey; Seated: Lil’ Keke, Big Moe, Mr. 3-2, 2010-024_00039.jpg (Item 24)
    - HAWK, Lil' O, and Big Moe, 2010-024_00040.jpg (Item 25)
    - Lil’ Harvey, Ant, Man Pooh, Lil' Keke, HAWK, Trae, and Mike Frost, 2010-024_00041.jpg (Item 26)
    - HAWK, Trae, Jay'Ton, and Lil Boss, 2010-024_00042.jpg (Item 27)
    - HAWK in green jersey, 2010-024_00043.jpg (Item 28)
    - Mike D., HAWK, and Tow Down, 2010-024_00044.jpg (Item 29)
    - HAWK and Papa Reu at car show, Reliant Stadium, 2010-024_00045.jpg, 2004 (Item 30)
    - Big Moe and HAWK at car show, Reliant Stadium, 2010-024_00046.jpg, 2004 (Item 31)
    - HAWK, Lil' O, and Big Moe at car show, Reliant Stadium, 2010-024_00047.jpg, 2004 (Item 32)
    - HAWK and Lil' Keke in front of Image Works, 2010-024_00050.jpg (Item 33)
    - Big Moe performing at a club, 2010-024_00051.jpg (Item 34)
    - Big Pokey performing at a club, 2010-024_00052.jpg (Item 35)
    - HAWK in front of trees, 2010-024_00053.jpg (Item 36)
    - HAWK speaking at Career Day at [Mading?] Elementary School, 2010-024_00054.jpg–2010-024_00055.jpg (Item 37)
    - Mesha and Tahj Hawkins, 2010-024_00056.jpg (Item 38)
    - HAWK speaking at Career Day at [Mading?] Elementary School, 2010-024_00057.jpg (Item 39)
    - Mac Biggers, unknown, Bleeder, HAWK, Sean Harris, and Trae, 2010-024_00058.jpg (Item 40)
    - Big Pokey and HAWK on stage, 2010-024_00059.jpg (Item 41)
    - HAWK on the mic at TSU arena, 2010-024_00060.jpg–2010-024_00061.jpg (Item 42)
    - HAWK in Brooklyn jersey, 2010-024_00062.jpg (Item 43)
    - Trae and HAWK at Club Konnections, 2010-024_00063.jpg–2010-024_00064.jpg (Item 44)
    - HAWK with Lil' Pat and Trae, 2010-024_00065.jpg (Item 45)
    - HAWK by equipment, 2010-024_00066.jpg (Item 46)
    - Unknown, unknown, Trae, Lil’ Pat, HAWK, Jay’Ton, and unknown, 2010-024_00067.jpg (Item 47)
    - Big Pokey, Trae, and HAWK, 2010-024_00068.jpg (Item 48)
    - Scarface, Momma Moe (Big Moe’s mother), HAWK, and Tahj Hawkins, 2010-024_00069.jpg (Item 49)
    - HAWK and Trae in jackets, 2010-024_00070.jpg (Item 50)
    - Trae, Lil' Pat, and HAWK in R.I.P. Fat Pat T-shirt, 2010-024_00071.jpg (Item 51)
    - Big Pokey and Lil' O, 2010-024_00072.jpg (Item 52)
    - Kay-K and Fat Pat At D.E.A. Screwed for Life photo shoot, 2010-024_00073.jpg (Item 53)
    - Big Pokey, Big Moe, and HAWK, 2010-024_00074.jpg (Item 54)
    - Chris Ward and Lil’ Keke at Kappa Beach Party, 2010-024_00075.jpg (Item 55)
    - HAWK, Lil’ Keke, and Lil’ Black, 2010-024_00076.jpg (Item 56)
  - Personal Photographs
    - Wedding
      - The Groovey Grill Mansion, 2010-024_00077.jpg, April 9, 2006 (Item 1)
      - Louella “Puddin” Hawkins and Patrick “Lil’ Pat” Hawkins, 2010-024_00078.jpg, April 9, 2006 (Item 2)
      - Barbarette Newton, aunt of the bride, 2010-024_00079.jpg, April 9, 2006 (Item 3)
      - Flower girls, 2010-024_00081.jpg, April 9, 2006 (Item 4)
      - Flower girls and little boy, 2010-024_00081.jpg, April 9, 2006 (Item 5)
      - Delano Duncan Jennings, mother of the bride, 2010-024_00082.jpg–2010-024_00083.jpg, April 9, 2006 (Item 6)
      - Minister, John "HAWK" Hawkins, and boys on porch, 2010-024_00084.jpg, April 9, 2006 (Item 7)
      - Meshah Henderson in gown, 2010-024_00086.jpg, April 9, 2006 (Item 8)
      - Meshah walking towards her mother, Delano Duncan Jennings, 2010-024_00086.jpg, April 9, 2006 (Item 9)
      - Meshah with her mother, Delano Duncan Jennings, 2010-024_00077.jpg, April 9, 2006 (Item 10)
      - Ceremony, 2010-024_00088.jpg, April 9, 2006 (Item 11)
      - Minister, Meshah, and HAWK, 2010-024_00089.jpg, April 9, 2006 (Item 12)
      - Meshah and HAWK, 2010-024_00090.jpg–2010-024_00091.jpg, April 9, 2006 (Item 13)
    - Funeral
      - Pallbearers and cemetery employees move Fat Pat’s casket from hearse to plot, HAWK in grey jacket, 2010-024_00048.jpg, February 7, 1998 (Item 1)
      - Pallbearers for Fat Pat gathered around hearse at cemetery, 2010-024_00049.jpg, February 7, 1998 (Item 2)
  - Newspaper Clippings
    - Houston Chronicle article, “Few clues in killing of Houston rapper,” 2010-024_00092a.jpg–2010-024_00092b.jpg, May 3, 2006 (Item 1)
    - Houston Chronicle obituary, 2010-024_00093.jpg, May 1, 2006 (Item 2)
    - Houston Chronicle article, “Hundreds mourn their ‘terrible loss’ at memorial service for ‘Big Hawk,’” 2010-024_00094.jpg, May 9, 2006 (Item 3)
    - Houston Chronicle article, “Final farewell,” 2010-024_00093.jpg, May 10, 2006 (Item 4)